Guide to the William Clair Turner Papers, circa 1960s-2013 UA.29.02.0250
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- United Holy Church of America Records
  - Northwestern District Convocation programs, 1958 and 1976 (Box 9)
  - Northwestern District Missionary Department historical review, 1985 (Box 9)
  - "An Overview of the Development of Sites 1 and 2, City of Durham, North Carolina," the Leon Bridges Company, 1981 (Box 9)
  - "Report of the Young People's Holy Association", 1983 (Box 9)
  - "Revival at Faith Gospel Tabernacle", undated (Box 9)
  - Sanford District Convention programs, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Southern District Convocation programs, 1975 and 2010 (Box 9)
  - "Standard Manual and Constitution and By-Laws of the United Holy Church of America, Incorporated", 1966 (Box 9)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. budgets, 1960-1972 (Box 9)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. Department of Education reports, 1952 (Box 9)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. doctrine, policies, and history, 1980-1981 and undated (Box 12)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. General Annual and Quadrennial Convocation minutes, 1966-1972 (Box 9)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. General Annual and Quadrennial Convocation minutes, 1975-1985 (Box 9)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. General Convocation programs, 1970-1991 (Box 9)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, 1965-1979 folder 1 of 2 (Box 9)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, 1965-1979 folder 2 of 2 (Box 9)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, 1972-1977 (Box 12)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, 1972-1977 (Box 13)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, 1972-1977 (Box 13)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, 1972-1977 (Box 13)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, 1974-1976 (Box 13)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, 1974-1986 (Box 9)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, 1975-1982 (Box 13)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, 1976-1978 (Box 13)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, 1984-1986 (Box 9)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. materials, undated (Box 9)
  - The United Holy Church of America, Inc. vs. the Original United Holy Church of the World, 1977 (Box 9)
  - United Holy Church of America, Inc. yearbook, 1928 (Box 9)
  - "The United Holy Church's Ecclesiology: History, Polity and Doctrine," by Elijah Williams, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Virginia District Convocation constitution, circa 1966 (Box 9)
  - Virginia District Convocation minutes, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Virginia District Convocation programs, 1977-1985 (Box 9)
  - "Wading through the Old Testament: An Old Testament Survey," by Elroy Lewis, 1988 (Box 9)
  - West Virginia District Convocation programs, 1980-1985 (Box 9)
  - Western North Carolina District Convocation minutes, 1974-1979 (Box 9)
  - Western North Carolina District Convocation minutes, 1980 (Box 9)
  - Western North Carolina District programs, 1975-1989 and undated (Box 10)
  - "Yearbook of the United Holy Church of America, Inc.", 1935 (Box 10)
  - Young People's Holy Association Quarterly, Oct.-Dec. 1956 - July-Sept. 1960 (Box 10)
  - Young People's Holy Association Quarterly, July-Sept. 1961 - Apr.-June 1968 (Box 10)
  - Young People's Holy Association Quarterly, Oct.-Dec. 1968- Jan.-March 1973 (Box 10)
  - Young People's Holy Association Quarterly, Apr.-June 1974 - July-Sept. 1976 (Box 10)
  - Young People's Holy Association Quarterly, Jan.-March 1977 - Oct.-Dec. 1981 (Box 10)
  - Young People's Holy Association Quarterly, Jan.-March 1983 - July-Sept. 1983 (Box 10)
  - Young People's Holy Association Quarterly, July-Sept. 1983 - Oct.-Dec. 1984 (Box 10)
  - Young People's Holy Association Quarterly, Oct.-Dec. 1984 - Jan.-March 1989 (Box 10)
- Subject Files
  Organized alphabetically, the subject files series comprises materials on various topics, some brought together by Turner and some by the archivist. Original folder titles are in quotation marks. Topics include areas of academic interest, churches pastored, civil rights ephemera, and reflections on Turner’s experience as a black student at Duke, including involvement with the Allen Building Takeover. The folders "Student Affairs" also include a report on black student attrition at Duke.
  - "The African American Catholic Congregation Movement under the Leadership of George Augustus Stallings, Jr: Newspaper and Magazine Articles," compiled by Jon Michael Spencer, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Faith Gospel Tabernacle United Holy Church materials, 1979-1981 and undated (Box 8)
  - Fisher Memorial United Holy Church materials, 1973-1975 (Box 11)
  - Fisher Memorial United Holy Church materials, 1975-1977 and undated (Box 8)
  - Fisher Memorial United Holy Church materials, 1976 and undated (Box 8)
  - Fisher Memorial United Holy Church materials, 1977-1979 (Box 11)
  - Fisher Memorial United Holy Church materials, undated (Box 8)
  - "Interdenominational Ministerial Alliance of Durham and Vicinity", 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - "Lincoln, C. Eric", 1978, 1982 and undated (Box 8)
  - "Mack's Chapel United Holy Church", 1986 and undated (Box 8)
  - "Magazine and newspaper clippings", circa 1980-2000 (Box 12)
  - "Magazine and newspaper clippings", circa 1980-2000 (Box 12)
  - "Magazine and newspaper clippings", circa 1980-2000 (Box 12)
  - "Magazine and newspaper clippings", circa 1980-2000 (Oversize-box 15)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. Commemoration Committee, 2006-2007 (Box 8)
    restricted until 2032
  - Mount Level Missionary Baptist Church Deacon Studies, 1999 (Box 8)
  - Newsweek, with cover article "Martin Luther King Jr., 1929-1968", 1968 April 15 (Box 8)
  - "On Aboriginal Religion," W. E. H. Stanner, 1960 (Box 12)
  - "Pentecostalism and UHCA miscellaneous", undated (Box 8)
  - "Pentecostalism and UHCA miscellaneous", undated (Box 12)
  - "Pentecostalism and UHCA miscellaneous", undated (Oversize-box 15)
  - "Pentecostals Reconciliation Dialogue", 1994 (Box 8)
  - "Practical Preaching in Zion: Somebody Ought to Say Something," Bishop Joseph Johnson, undated (Box 8)
  - "Pictures, etc. from Pre-Civil Rights South", 1958-1965 (Box 8)
  - "Student Affairs", 1975-1977 (Box 8)
  - "Student Affairs", 1975-1977 (Box 8)
  - "Society for Pentecostal Studies," Sixteenth Annual Meeting, 1986 Nov. 13-15 (Box 8)
  - "Society for Pentecostal Studies," Sixteenth Annual Meeting, 1986 Nov. 13-15 (Box 8)
  - "Theomusicology and Miscellaneous Articles", 1989-1990 (Box 8)
  - "My Vision Becoming a Reality" Deacon and Deaconess Class, 2013 (Box 8)
  - William Turner and black student life at Duke, 1985-1991 and undated (Box 12)
  - Wilmington Ten materials, 1976 (Box 8)
- Personal Papers
  This series contains Turner's personal materials such as copies of his resume, daily planners, collected ephemera, awards, and syllabi, class notes, and papers from his time as an undergraduate and graduate student at Duke. Student materials are ordered chronologically where the date is known, ending with dissertation materials, while the other folders are alphabetical.
  - OT 11, Fall 1970 (Box 4)
  - "The Blues Men: Priests, Theologians, Philosophers" and other papers and notes, 1970-1972 (Box 4)
  - Class notes, readings, and papers, 1970-1978 (Box 5)
  - Class notes, readings, and papers, 1970-1978 (Box 5)
  - Class notes, readings, and papers, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - Class notes, readings, syllabi, and papers, 1972-1976 and undated (Box 5)
  - "The Use of Scripture in Christian Ethics" and other papers and notes, 1973 and undated (Box 5)
  - Book summaries, 1977 and undated (Box 5)
  - Class syllabi and papers, 1977-1980 (Box 5)
  - "Afro-Americans and the Great Awakening", 1978 (Box 5)
    copy 1
  - "Afro-Americans and the Great Awakening", 1978 (Box 5)
    copy 2
  - Class notes, Fall 1978 (Box 5)
  - "Handbook on the Study of Religion" collection of papers and notes, 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Class syllabi and papers, 1979-1980 and undated (Box 5)
  - "Notes", undated (Box 5)
  - "Notes on Fathers' Preaching and Paper and Luke", undated (Box 5)
  - Materials from Professor C. K. Robinson, undated (Box 5)
  - Class notes, undated (Box 5)
  - "Black Theology, Black Evangelism" and other papers, undated (Box 5)
  - "Black Theology, Black Evangelism", undated (Box 5)
  - "Black Theology, Black Evangelism", undated (Box 5)
    copy 3
  - "Dissertation Draft", undated (Box 5)
  - "Redrafted Chapters, Sections, etc.", undated (Box 5)
  - "Notes for Dissertation Redrafting", undated (Box 5)
  - Dissertation materials, undated (Box 5)
  - "The United Holy Church of America: A Study in Black Holiness-Pentecostalism", undated (Box 5)
  - "The United Holy Church of America: A Study in Black Holiness-Pentecostalism", undated (Box 6)
  - "The United Holy Church of America: A Study in Black Holiness-Pentecostalism", undated (Box 6)
  - Certificates and plaques, 1979-2007 and undated (Box 10)
  - Church programs, 1974-1979 (Box 10)
  - Church programs, 1980-1983 (Box 10)
  - Church programs, 1997 and undated (Box 10)
  - Commencement and reunion programs, 1974-2006 (Box 10)
  - Curriculum vitae and photographs, undated (Box 10)
  - "Daily Meditations and Other Entries", 1983 (Box 10)
  - Diary, 1978 (Box 10)
  - Diary, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Diary, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
  - Diary, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Diary, circa 2002-2008 (Box 10)
  - Ephemera, 1964-1986 (Box 10)
  - Ephemera, 1987-2013 and undated (Box 10)
  - Ephemera, 1964-2013 (Oversize-box 15)
  - Publications, 1970-1976 (Box 14)
  - Publications, 1977-2013 (Box 14)
  - "Celebrating the Turner Legacy," Gatherings, Summer 2008 (mounted article with handwritten notes) (Oversize-box 59)